Yiru (Ru) Zhou

(773) 850 9031 | yiruzhou2020@u.northwestern.edu

Summary

Creative problem-solver with demonstrated enthusiasm in the practice of mission-driven work. Unique interpersonal communication to build meaningful relationships with stakeholders. Knowledge of education, project management and customer experience. Extensive experience as a detail-oriented administrator with a passion for solving problems and promoting hope through accessibility and inclusivity. Multicultural background and highly adaptable to different professional cultures and social contexts.

Education

Career Foundry Certificate
User Experience (UX) Design
Northwestern University School of Communication, Evanston, IL

Master of Science in Leadership for Creative Enterprises
Scholarship Recipient
School of the Art Institute of Chicago, Chicago, IL

Bachelor of Fine Art with an Emphasis in Fiber Art and Arts Administration
Merit Scholarship Recipient

2023-2024

2019-2020

2019-2020

2019-2020

Professional Experience

Art Teacher | Denver Parks and Recreation, Denver, CO

6/2023-Present

- Implement both youth and adult art classes to Denver residents
- Develop curriculums that focus on art history and techniques
- Support Parks and Recreation's community events and festivals

Language Services Advisor | Translation Excellence, Denver, CO

9/2023-11/2023

- Provide clients from 8+ industries with satisfactory solutions to their language services needs
- Research and construct business development plans to expand market share
- Oversee and manage translation projects from start to customer hand-off

Public School Teacher (SEL)| Denver Language School, Denver, CO

12/2018-1/2023

- Engage 25+ students with difficulties learning in creative inspiration and motivation
- Manage 20 classrooms of 30 students with abundant educational tactics
- Create and organize 50+ teaching materials and engagement materials
- Build strong relationships with 600 students of different needs during each school year
- Manage deadlines and monitor multiple student evaluation projects

Art Programming Intern | Awakenings Art, Chicago, IL

6/2020-9/2020

- Curated new virtual exhibition of survivor art within 3 months
- Increased accessibility of large permanent collection
- Optimized audiences' engagement level by 30%
- Reviewed artwork/literature submission and delivered valuable feedback in decision-making process
- Collaborated with marketing department on launching new virtual program
- Executed creative responses and reviews to permanent artwork collection

Communication Intern | Telluride Arts District, Telluride, CO

11/2016-4/2017

- Streamlined production process of organization's merchandise
- Showcased creative insights on curating seasonal art exhibition
- Managed 5+artists in residency on promotion/marketing
- Promoted artwork on-view with education and active engagement with community

Extra-Curriculars

Visual Art Committee Member | Awakenings Art, Chicago, IL

1/2020-Present

Skills

Project Management | Organization | Administration | Education | Learning Management System (Schoology) | Design Software | Writing | Communication | Bilingual (Mandarin) | Google Workspace | Office 365 | Customer Experience